The moment you put money in, I'm going to name the podcast "Man, Gambels, Childs."
Don't delete the key. Point your claw at the code. Ask Claude if we delete the keys. Claude
will say yes. Yeah, you're basically trusting them not to flip that pool in the same way
that you're trusting Coinbase to let you process withdrawals in the future. So it seems fairly
custodial to me.
Like a video game for 10 seconds in your browser to post or something like that. Proof of
fun to post.
Jeff can do that for, you know, one cent.
Yo, yo, everybody. It's the permanent under pod. I'm talking to a chopstick and this is
Jackson Cook.
Hey, it's Tyler. I'm talking into this microphone holder that you could maybe pick up the sushi
with. I don't know. I've never tried it before. On to you, Chris.
It's Chris. No further comments. I end my turn.
I don't think you want your microphone smelling like fish for the rest of your life, Tyler.
It seems like a bad name.
Yeah, I think Chris won that round of intros. The only winning move is not to play the game.
I needed a win. So thank you.
I'm really liking the this is like the perfect amount of shadow to mustache. I think Chris
is looking crispy. Good facial curvature. You're looking clavicular out there. Thanks.
Thank you. But my clavicles are down here. But I appreciate the sentiment.
You're mandicular. And here we go. Straight into the perp of fortune, where Chris and
I put real United States dollars into leverage perpetual futures in pursuit of fortune or
destitution. Well, Tyler tells us we didn't go hard enough on the leverage. Chris, what's
the damage?
All right. So it's queuing up right now. I promise. But let me read out the thesis to
you. The thesis is long after on perp trading becoming spectator entertainment, not long
on Korea, which that feels like a shot fired. I don't know what's happening here. So it
says there. Yeah, it says that the catalyst is that Astor sponsored rebound X's September
28 live trading competition in Seoul, which I think we're going to get into next. And
basically, it's betting that there's going to be more of these competitions. They're
going to get more popular. And then traders will bid up Astor as a result because it's
connected to these live perp competitions. So yep.
Besides being a sponsor, what is Astor?
I think it is. Is it a perps exchange? Astor perps.
I see.
Yeah, it's making any sense for any other business to sponsor this competition. Would
it surprise you if they were like, we make water bottles. Why a perp trading competition?
Who is the sponsor of this cigarette smoking competition? Oh, weird. It's the tobacco company.
I don't know if I've mentioned my passion for the two Rubik's cubes, two beers, two
cigarettes challenge, but I think that's a really cool challenge. What order is the challenge
conducted in? Oh, well, you get to optimize for your own skill. Choose your own adventure.
Okay. I think most people do start with a beer to loosen up the hands for the cubes.
And then you're either puffing the saying while you're, you know, twisting the cube,
or I feel like you'd want to do one cigarette to get all jacked up on nicotine, rip the
two cubes, chug the two beers and then finish up with a post two beer cigarette. How is
that so obvious to me? You might want to enjoy the cigarette at that point. You don't want
to enjoy it. You want to smoke it down. Chris, resident cigarette expert, what do you think?
I think I could smoke a cigarette very fast. I think the Rubik's Cuban beer would be a little
bit more difficult, but I think the cigarettes are non-event. You could put them in anywhere.
I think the world record time is at like one minute, 20 seconds. It's really the bottleneck
because your ability to solve a Rubik's cube. Because most of us can smoke an entire cigarette
in one breath.
Does it have to be cereal? Like are they combining two or three activities at once? Like can
you Rubik's whilst you're like smoking it or like beer?
Yeah.
Oh, I assume that you're like light two cigarettes, put them in, and then you just Rubik's cube.
I haven't seen anyone go walrus on it. I think that is a good strategy.
Anyways, sorry, last comment on the competition.
I was going to say like going gorilla mode, but then I think going walrus mode is the
new, really going berserk.
The thumbnail will be Chris with two cigarettes while we're singing out of his, I mean, because
you have the mustache. Anyways, so the really cool thing, the perp competition. Chris, you
are our resident gambling expert. How long have these been going on?
I'm sorry, I'm on the hook for cigarettes and gambling, just setting a terrible precedent.
You need to rewrite your resume.
Apparently. So I have no idea how long this has been going on. I basically just saw it
on Twitter. You know, Korea is famous for things like esports and the excellent reality
TV shows.
I was going to say, as a resident Korea expert, I feel like this is the perfect Korean activity
because it combines esports and gambling, basically, which is essentially their love
of high-leverage stock trading, which is essentially gambling.
Exactly.
Yeah.
But when it comes to perpetual futures, Chris is the man. He knew what Asta was. He knows
what Hyperliquid is.
I barely knew what Asta was. There are so many perps DEXs. Sorry, Asta, if you want to sponsor
the podcast, I will take this back. But there are a lot of perps DEXs out there. So yeah,
I wasn't sure.
It sounds like Asta is trying to throw some money, so don't be throwing shade in their
direction.
I think it's a great product. Yeah, I think it's a great product and we're up 9 cents.
I think the implication is that their head of marketing watches the pod and got the idea
from this purpose trading competition from Purple Fortune.
So they already owe us, like they already owe us royalties for this.
Yeah.
How do we get in on it too? I want to play.
Even our amazing track record of selecting great perps on the pod.
Chris sent us that clip of the person making $40,000 and all we've done is lose $100 or
gain $6. What are they doing? Why don't we get enough leverage? Maybe we need to go to
Asta so we can go like 1000X.
So that person, I think, is actually a famous online streamer, Korean streamer, who just
does perps trading. There's a clip of her perps trading one of Donald Trump's speeches
and just freaking out every time he says Bitcoin because she has like a 50X Bitcoin long on
or something.
That's amazing.
So this really is a way of life. I think we are new to this game and we have to be respectful.
Yeah, drop a comment if you'd like to have a co-stream of us and a presidential speech
where we're trading perps on Donny's words. We need to get a quick signal on the ground.
So how does a perps trading competition work? Does everyone start with some kind of buy-in
amount and then it's just like you deposit it in your account and whoever has the most
money at the end of some time period wins?
I really don't know. Someone said it was paper trading, which is actually so disappointing
to me.
Oh yeah, because like you need to account for like position size and stuff like that.
Like if you just go gig along some micro cap and then it goes up on paper, but you don't
have to actually like liquidate your position and then nuke the whole position, then yeah.
Totally. Nothing ventured. Yeah. 100%. But yeah, I do. I think perps are coming back.
I get this. I get this really weird feeling on the back of my neck that everyone is in
my inbox, that everybody really wants to do perps right now, and they need guys to do
perps for them. So I think perps are going to be very huge very soon. I know that Robinhood,
did they just start? They just like have started pushing their perps. And I think a lot of
other venues are getting there very quickly.
Well, if anyone needs advice on how to build a perp platform, I watched the Kraken YouTube
video and read the Investopedia article on perps, so I'm pretty much an expert on the
math behind it.
Yeah, and we're out here in the arena, wagering. Well, some of us wagering hundreds of dollars.
What's our leverage on Astra, by the way, Astra?
It's only 5x. Yeah, it's pathetic. A liquid shitcoin. Sorry, again, sorry, Astra. I didn't
mean it.
Tyler, doesn't even need to say anything. Tyler, we know. We know we messed up.
I'm going to start spreading the conspiracy that the two of you are also paper trading
for perp of fortune. That's why you won't let me add money into the pot is because the
pot doesn't exist. It's all a charade. I'm going to expose this nefarious activity. I
don't know why you'd be doing this conspiracy yet, but I think I'm on to it.
The moment you put money in, I'm going to name the podcast Man Gambels Child's College
Education Fund for Perpetual Fortune.
I just took all of my daughter's Trump account books and put them into 100X Astra.
That's actually a big business idea. How can we allow a Trump account to trade perp? Is
that available today?
Perpifying the children's money. I cannot think of something more unambiguously good.
Enough with the perps though. A lot of perps today, a lot of Korea, but a little bit more
on the perp. The perp was chosen by a new technology discovered in the LOM space, Jev.
Scientists were using their telescope in space and discovered a new LOM technology.
They were like, what if we just cut out all the wares and stop it at the token probability
piece? Is that basically it? Is that how you guys understand Jev? Give me a breakdown.
Jev is a new type of model and the whole selling point is that it has a structured output.
You could ask it questions and then it's been trained so that it only responds in the structures
that you define. Then you define these structures. They're typed. They're supposed to be type-safe.
Then also they output probabilities for different questions that you would ask it. You could
ask it, "Is this spam?" Then it will give you a probability from zero to one. Or, "Here's
customer request. Can you categorize it among these 10 categories and give me the probabilities
of each of them?" It helps you make quick decisions based on a text input.
I would say that the main reason... I think that this form factor is something that obviously
has really struck a nerve and that people are really excited about. I think it's a very
powerful thing. I don't think it's a new thing. Classifier models that output probabilities.
I think that the new-ish thing is that previously, if you wanted that model where you were like,
"Which of these 10 customer support queues should this text go to?" You could train
your own model to output that thing. You could get an off-the-shelf open source language
model. You could pop a new layer onto it and then train it on your own proprietary data
to basically take advantage of the pre-training. This is called transfer learning. That takes
some technical know-how. It takes you to curate a dataset. It takes you to get at least one
GPU to train it. I've done a bunch of this type of thing in the past.
With this, I think it's just relying on the general intelligence of the model that it's
built on top of so that you can basically just rely on that general intelligence and
then try to structure what you want upfront. You don't have to do that training. You don't
have to curate the dataset. You just trust that the model is well calibrated and generally
smart enough to give you a mostly good enough answer.
That's my take. I feel like the form factor is obviously something that's super valuable.
I don't think it's a new concept of having a model that would output this type of output.
I think it just enables it for a bunch of very long-tail cases that previously were
not economically viable for a company or developer to do on their own because it requires hiring
a data scientist and curating a dataset and then doing the transfer learning and knowing
a little bit about this. Now you can just point your API key at OpenRouter and get a
pretty good answer.
Totally. I haven't looked at Jev too much, but I understood that it's faster than a normal
language model at these tasks, but obviously it's much more generalizable than a pre-trained
classifier. That was my vibe on the situation. Does that sound right to you?
I think so. I think that's their selling point. I don't think there's any inherent reason
why it's faster than a language model. You can imagine that you just have a very small
language model and you don't have it reasoned very much and then you optimize it a little
bit and that's basically what Jev is. I suspect that they're taking some off-the-shelf open
weights model and then they are basically curated their big dataset of all these different
structured types and they put a layer on that tries to constrain what the outputs are and
then they did a bunch of their own training to calibrate it in that way. I suspect that
they are not fresh pre-training their own thing. It's probably the same thing under
the hood. It just has this extra layer on it and it's been a little bit optimized for
it and there's no reason that any other company that does language models couldn't do that,
I think.
Yeah. I don't think that Jev has any moat, but some of the applications I've seen Jev
in so far are real-time adjacent. Jev plays Doom or Jev does some sort of real-time task.
That's why I mentioned the speed and latency thing because if you imagine a frontier model
doing that, there's just too much reasoning going on to be feasible.
I don't understand how Jev actually plays Doom because Jev doesn't do image input. The
input that Jev is getting about the state of the Doom game has to be told to it via
text somehow, some kind of structured input that describes the state of Doom to it and
then it can make a determination. So there's some kind of middleware in there. I don't
know how that is working, but yeah, it can't take an image and then make a decision.
It sounds like they are doing that, that somehow turning those pixels into a series of decisions
and that Jev makes them.
So you're telling me, Tyler, that if it's the same LLM under the hood, that they're
just slapping on basically an additional prompt to structure your output, something that we've
been doing, or me and Chris have been doing as engineers for a year and it's all marketing
boy.
I think it's a little bit more than that. It's not just like they created a good system
prompt and then their model is forced. They definitely did some kind of fine tuning to
their thing and some optimizations and stuff like that. So it's not quite that simple.
My notes here said that Jev beat Pokemon Red in 37 hours for $1.65 using Claude Opus 5.
These headlines are out of control. These headlines are out of control. We need to talk
about headline inflation.
The part at the end where it's using Claude Opus 5. Wait, so is Jev playing or is Claude
playing?
Did they Jevify Claude Opus 5?
They used Claude to build a harness for Jev to run Jev.
Confusing headline made by my AI note generator. We'll have to dig into that one.
One thing that I think is interesting about Jev that I think you kind of touched on Tyler
is that it's not like this was impossible before. They're putting some kind of layer
on top of Jev that forces it to do classification tasks and they're using some, like you said,
some post-train of an open-weights model maybe.
But it took this long for people to, I don't know, like find a viable product or find a
viable form factor for like a Jev form factor for these language models.
Yeah, I just I wonder like what else is unexplored in the language model probability space that
would be really useful that we haven't thought about yet? Because it seems like everybody's
pushing the frontier, right? Like everybody wants the fabled tier or Astra tier intelligence.
But it seems like there's all these really good completely unexplored, unoptimized use
cases like further down the sort of like intelligence gradient. And yeah, I just I wonder what the
other Jevs will be.
Yeah, I think it like clearly is a very, it's going to, it's an innovation that's going
to stick on like the form factor and the output type for sure, I think. I do think it's kind
of interesting, like at the end of the day, it's still kind of a vibe. So like, let's
say that you ask Jev like, I don't know, like, what is the probability of it raining tomorrow?
And then you ask it, what is the probability of it not raining tomorrow? Like the sum of
those two things won't equal one. Because like, because like, within each of those separate
things, it will kind of like, just make its own determination. And I don't think it's
very scientific. But it does output some answer that's like, approximately calibrated. So
I think it's like pretty rough, vibey. It's like, if you asked Chris, and he was like,
you know, pretty smart about whether, whether it's going to rain tomorrow or not, and he'd
be like, I don't know, man, like 60%. And that's just off the top of his head based
on like, you know, what's in his brain. That's kind of what Jev is doing, as far as I understand,
it's like, what's in my brain is my water weights. And I'm just going to output a number
based on what feels good in those model weights.
Okay, so my pushback firstly, one, they call me the weatherman. So thank you. But secondly,
I think there are viable tasks, right? Like, I think you can vibe a vacuum clean your house,
you know what I mean? Like, I think there is like, I mean, like, what are the consequences
of your vacuum taking a right instead of a left, right, as opposed to, you know, the
benefit that you would get from having like a kind of like generalized model that's able
to like navigate around obstacles or make decisions about what to do. And maybe there
are more layers and guardrails you can put on top of Jev's for these like, viable real
time tasks that might be useful. I don't know. Just a thought.
You're saying maybe Jev would be a way to accelerate like robotics, development, like
put a Jev into a robot and then put guardrails around it. So it doesn't bust through the
wall trying to vacuum your closet.
Totally. I don't want like these lame pre-trained algorithmic robots that like map the floor
plan and like do the same thing every time. Like I want the mouse droid from Star Wars.
I think like that's Jev, like that's a Jev task. So maybe everyone disagrees with me.
Jev is coming in. That's a good question. We will see as time passes how Jev ends up
being used. But now this time we transition to everyone's favorite style of topic on the
podcast. It's the biggest. It's the most humongous. It's a Bitcoin topic.
We're going to talk today about a Bitcoin layer two called Spark, which is created by
a company called LightSpark, which is created by a dude who created Libra.
He created it at David Marcus. Libra never existed.
We were never able to get any Libra. Was it like cut off?
In our hearts and minds we were. Yeah. We talked about it a lot. I definitely talked
about it a lot. Libra was announced when I was very deep in the industry.
That's like cosmetology or astrology. As in whether it's real or not.
I thought Libra was one of the... The analogy still holds up. Ambiguously true.
But Tyler, please tell us about... I don't know. There's so many things to get into.
Maybe first describe what is a layer two for Bitcoin and then tell us what does Spark bring
to the table that Bitcoin's layer one doesn't.
Okay, this is an insanely deep topic. I'll try to keep it pretty high level.
But yeah, a Bitcoin layer two, the general concept is that the layer one of Bitcoin is
the blockchain and the blockchain doesn't scale very well because it has a limited amount
of transaction throughput and it's limited because you want to keep blocks small.
And that means that you can only put so many transactions in them and you want to keep
blocks small because you want to make it easy for anyone to run the Bitcoin software.
And if blocks are too big, then it is going to increase how expensive of a computer you
need, how big of an internet connection you need. There's a lot of things there that makes
it harder.
So we keep blocks small. That means we can't do a lot of transactions. That means we need
to figure out some other way for people to do transactions on Bitcoin if we want it to
scale to be more than just a hobbyist kind of network.
So people are trying to invent constructs called layer twos, which are different types
of protocols that you can transact Bitcoin with. And in general, they try to take your
transactions and keep them off of the blockchain, but still maintain a lot of the assurances
that you would get by holding Bitcoin, which is stuff like you can't be easily censored.
You have self custody. You can always exit from the layer two back to the L1 without
anyone's permission. So you can always have your Bitcoin yourself, that kind of stuff.
And there's a bunch of layer twos that have been proposed. The most prominent ones are
probably the Lightning Network, Spark, Arc. There's state chains. There's a bunch of other
ones. But we're talking about Arc today. Okay. Ariel, is that a good, good high level summary?
You prompted me to give what is a layer two. So that was beautiful. Okay. So Spark is a
layer two that was invented maybe two years ago.
And I think it builds a lot on prior systems, which is pretty common. And I think it's most
similar to state chains. But the kind of high level idea is that there's this thing called
the Spark. And that is basically the protocol that you operate in. It's operated by a set
of companies. And these companies are the Spark entity. And basically, it's a federated
system where if I have Bitcoin outside of the Spark and I pay Jackson, I can pay him
via the Lightning Network. And he can receive that Bitcoin within the Spark as kind of like
Spark Bitcoin. And whenever Jackson then wants to pay Chris, he can pay Chris within the
Spark. But it essentially requires the cooperation of a majority of the federation that operates
the Spark. And so you can either pay people within the Spark, and that's very cheap, or
they have these things called the SSPs, the Spark service providers, which do swaps between
Spark Bitcoin and essentially Lightning Bitcoin, or on-chain Bitcoin.
And so that's the way that you would have... You could hold your money in Spark. You can
pay anyone that accepts Lightning by doing these SSP swaps. All of this requires the
cooperation of the Spark entity. And there are some kind of tricky trade-offs with Spark
as there is for any L2. You always have to make trade-offs and figure out what the right
security model balance is.
The main one for Spark, I would say, is that the security requires you to trust that the
Spark entity is deleting the old keys. So every time Jackson pays Chris within the Spark,
basically, you can think about it almost like a 202 multi-sig, where it's like Jackson and
the Spark both have keys for this. And then when they sign it over to Chris, they both
have to sign. And if the Spark entity were to keep the key that it used to sign that
prior transaction, then in the future, they can collude to steal the Bitcoin back from
Chris.
So you have to trust that they don't hold on to that private key material. And there's
no way that they can prove that they deleted it. You just have to take their word for it.
You can't prove that they deleted it. And it goes a little bit further than that, which
is that you can't even really trust that they might say or they might try to in the future
be like, "Our code is open source." You can see that there's nothing in the code that
says like, "Don't delete the key. Point your cloud at the code. Ask Claude if we delete
the keys. Claude will say yes." But you don't actually know that that's the software they're
running. They could potentially run that software in like a Nitro Enclave. And then the Nitro
Enclave can do a cryptographic attestation that says they're running the software that
you can see the source code for, that your Claude told you that they delete the keys.
But I don't think they're doing that right now. And even then, I don't know how strong
I would believe.
Yeah.
There are flaws to that approach, I would say, even running in a Nitro Enclave. There
are ways around it, but it's good. It's good.
Yeah. So at the end of the day, the idea around any layer two is that you shouldn't have to
have trust in a custodian. And Spark is a selective custodian. As long as they're not
deleting keys, or as long as they are deleting keys, it's non-custodial. But they can choose
to or be compelled to hold on to old key material basically at any point. And you wouldn't really
have any idea that they were doing that.
And so the way that I've explained this to people in the past jokingly is it would be,
what if Coinbase said, "Well, you can always get your Bitcoin out of Coinbase because we're
publishing our source code. And you can see right here that we have a flag that says process
withdrawals equals true. And we haven't flipped that flag. So Coinbase is not custodial because
you can get your keys out because process withdrawals equals true. Spark is almost exactly
like that, where in theory, essentially in their code, they have a Boolean that's like
delete the key material true. And as long as that is true, that means it's not custodial,
but they could flip that bull and then you wouldn't be able to withdraw your Bitcoin.
Or they could take the Bitcoin whenever you do try to transact it. So yeah, you're basically
trusting them not to flip that bull the same way that you're trusting Coinbase to let you
process withdrawals in the future. So it seems fairly custodial to me.
Yeah. So a couple of points that come to mind here. One, has anyone heard of the term proof
of authority? This was a term that was bandied around in the outside of Bitcoin community,
I think when proof of stake was being discussed, there were these three types of networks that
you could have. There was proof of work, proof of stake, and proof of authority. And so proof
of work and proof of stake, we know what they are. Like proof of work, you compute the hash
proof of stake, you prove that you have some number of the token to bid on a slot. Proof
of authority was just like, well, there are these people that we trust and each one of
them runs a node, right? And we know who they are, we've seen their passports, something
like that. And it sounds a lot like that. Back in the day when there was a lot of bridging
going on, there were a lot of proof of authority bridges. I'm thinking of Ronan and wormhole
as two examples. Wormhole famously was like, there was this joke that it was a multi-sig
between friends because it was literally just...
Is it wormhole, like the jump trading like bridge?
Correct.
It's just like the come get scalped by these professional traders and use our bridge bridge.
Come get scalped until it gets obliterated for 300 million by Lazarus and then it must
have been making so much money that they just filled that hole. So yeah, I mean...
Let me go use this bridge that's operated by this swarm of sharks.
Completely undecentralized, by the way. Super cool. Yeah, I think it reminds me a little
bit of that. Typically, when protocols would say there were proof of authority, they would
have these elaborate plans to decentralize, which never happened, of course. But it sounds
like this is the network operating as expected. So something to think about.
Yeah. I think two other things I wanted to cover with Spark. One is the story around
unilateral exit, which is possible when they first launched. I don't think that they had
actually built a software tool for you to do this. And people kind of made some noise
about it and then they subsequently did. And the thing about the unilateral exit is the
most commonly, Spark is being pitched these days. It's like, put your spending wallet
on it or use it to onboard millions of users in the developing world. So that means they'll
probably have relatively small balances.
And then also, when you transact a lot on Spark, your Bitcoin tends to get broken up
into multiple leaves, what they call them. But you can think about them as roughly similar
UTXOs on layer 1. But so you have a lot of small valued leaves of Spark. And each of
those leaves needs to be unilaterally exit and the cost basically explodes the more leaves
you have and also the deeper the leaves get.
And so you can have a wallet where it costs a very significant portion of the wallet and
transaction fees in order to actually unilaterally exit. So this guy, Open Noms, who is a legend
hacker in the Bitcoin space, he builds raspy blitz and stuff like that. And he works for
Blink, which is a lightning wallet. He ran this test on Spark, where he tried to withdraw...
He had a $100,000 Satoshi wallet. So that's about $100 at the time, I think, maybe a little
bit less.
And he tried to use this unilateral exit thing. And his wallet had 22 leaves and it required
253 transaction packages to exit. And it cost him something like 80% of the wallet value
and on-chain fees to recover the other 20%.
So you have to spend 80,000 Satoshis to recover 20,000 Satoshis out of the Spark and in a
unilateral exit. So that's basically uneconomical in terms of the story for unilateral exit
for small amounts. So that's pretty bad.
Another thing there is that in order to do this unilateral exit, you need this recovery
backup that basically backs up the state of your wallet. And as far as I know, no consumer
wallets that are doing Spark make this available to the user or do something like iCloud backup
where it is being made available.
And so if you don't have this data, when you suddenly need the unilateral exit, you're
shadow luck. So I think that's something that might be a little bit overlooked in the ecosystem.
So that's the story about unilateral exit.
And then the last thing is the privacy story. Spark is not private. As far as I understand,
it could be. I think the technology to make this kind of construct private from the operators
exists, but they, I think, have made a choice not to make it private from the operators.
So when you transact on Spark, all of your transaction activity is viewable and attributable
to you by the Spark entity.
So just know that, that it's basically a custodial privacy kind of situation. And in the past,
it was even worse than that, where I think that they had an account model. So you weren't
creating a new address every time you received Spark, you were receiving and sending out
of the same address constantly. So that means that if somebody had your address, they could
see all your transaction activity.
And by default, all of the Spark transaction activity was published on a public block explorer
for funsies. There was no reason to do this other than I don't really understand why.
I think they were trying to go for a token trading speculation use case. And so they
were trying to pattern match the Ethereum Solana world, where that's more the case.
But yeah, so basically all of your transaction activity was... It wasn't like it was published
on some blockchain. And that's why there's a block explorer because it needs to be public.
It was like, this is a private ledger that has no reason to be public, but then they're
publishing it for the sake of transparency, which is kind of a head scratcher.
I believe now that you can set a flag in your Spark wallet that opts you out of that public
sharing. But yeah, I don't think by default, Spark has very good privacy from the public
and it doesn't have privacy at all from the Spark entity itself.
Wow. I mean, poor Spark just got torn apart.
I mean, in terms of publicly publishing something, it's like, okay, it's not public, even if
they don't publish it, but it's still not private, right? The Spark operators can see
all of your transactions. And if subpoenaed or if coerced somehow, they would be able
to turn those over to an authority, right? Or anyone, right? I think that's the fear.
I want to say one thing. There is a canonical way to decentralize these types of networks.
And I have to talk about it because I've done it. So the typical way to serve one of these
like L2s or out of band networks, like maybe you're serving an exchange out of a threshold
SIG or something like that, is you can do like some kind of bootleg version of proof
of stake, right? Where the validators in this case would be the Spark operators are talking
to each other and following a series of rules and committing every increment of the rules
that they're allowed to act upon to a shared blockchain. And when one of them goes out
of line, the others all vote to slash, which is to say, the others all vote to take away
some of their stake, right? So basically, punishing malfeasance for validators.
Does that work with the validators are all homies and business together?
It does not ask me how I got permission. It does not. It does not like you need you need
at least two, like, you know, let's say 303030 is the smallest ideal ratio or what is called
the Nakamoto coefficient, which is how many actual individual entities are validating the
network, not how many different nodes, how many individual entities. So that's the important
number for these proof of stake, progressive decentralized, like, like, obviously not fully
decentralized, but progressive decentralization schemes.
I don't know how meaningfully the fact that spark is operated by a federation. I don't
know how meaningful that is right now. Like, there's a world where it could be very meaningful
if the Federation is quite large and composed of like, unrelated energies, and etc, etc.
I think the default spark, so that that's one thing to mention, maybe is that like,
the spark code is open source, in theory, we could run a spark and we could be three
spark entities. But I don't believe there's any competing spark. The main spark is run
by, I believe, LightSpark, FlashNet and Breeze are the three companies that operate it. And
I don't believe anyone else is running one.
I think this is like from a protocol perspective, I think this is a reasonable bet to make when
you look over the fence at what protocols like Tempo are doing, which are unabashedly
just full on proof of authority networks, right? So, like, in that vein, and Tempo is
obviously not the only one who has made this decision, I think in that vein, in terms of
a business decision, I can see how if one entity is making that like, regulatory bet,
you would also make that same bet. But yeah, something to think about.
Yeah, totally. It makes a lot of sense. And I think that this was conceived of maybe before
there were like a lot of breakthroughs like on the arc side. And I think now a protocol
like arc looks like it has a lot of the benefits of spark, but with I think a much better trust
model, like a unilaterally better trust model. And that's even without covenants. And if
there ends up being a covenant soft fork that then enables the better forms of arc that
people want to see, then I think that those are like strictly superior. So I'll be interested
to see if spark survives in a world like that, or maybe if they get enough momentum and enough
activity and they're spark and they don't feel any drive to upgrade it to something
like that, or maybe they don't agree that arc is unilaterally better.
I do think it's worth maybe saying a few nice things about spark. So that was a little bit
of a tear down. But yeah, I think the main things that are really nice about spark is
I think that they have like an amazing SDK and like developer experience where I think
it's probably the easiest Bitcoin, L2 Bitcoin transaction thing to build into any app and
to like build a wallet around. It's not a super high bar because I think that the other
ones like Lightning Network are like kind of infamously complex. But yeah, I think spark
has made that probably as smooth as it could possibly be. I think that it enables people
to transact with Bitcoin very cheaply and very fast. And so it's like getting more people
using Bitcoin, hopefully, and trying to promote transactional use cases for Bitcoin. Is there
anything else you guys want to touch upon?
Yeah, also plugging into the existing rails, man. So one issue with Lightning has always
been that you have to have your Lightning node online for it to be fully self-custodial,
right? Otherwise, you're going through a Lightning provider in some configuration. I think Spark
unlocks out for a lot of people because of their federated setup that you can rail out
on Lightning, your Bitcoin super fast. I think that's cool.
Well, shout out to LightSpark. We don't hate Spark in entirety. We just pointed out many
of its potential flaws and the arc is going to L2MOG Spark in the short term. Thank you,
Tyler, for teaching us about Spark. So much more information than I learned for reading
the Spark blog comparing Bitcoin L2s. Moving on, all right. That's right. Final topic,
the slop auction. Our very own Chris Doran wrote another beautiful blog talking about
the slop that's polluting our feeds and filling up the internet. Chris, tell us, how do we
end this auction and stop the slop?
All right. So there's this famous thing in MEV, Maximum Extractable Value. There's a
famous post by the kings of MEV called Flashbots, where basically what they said is, so blockchains
have this scalability limit problem. Everybody wants to transact there. How do you decide
who gets to transact? And then how do you make sure that there is enough space in each
block in the blockchain to service all of the genuine transactions that people will
want to do?
And basically, Flashbots went across a bunch of L2s and they were like, "Let's look at
what the actual transactions on these L2s are composed of." And overwhelmingly, it's
not genuine transactions. It's the transactions that these L2s are mostly servicing are MEV
transactions. So when you're on chain...
How is a MEV transaction not a real transaction? Doesn't there have to be some associated economic
activity for it to vampire in order for there to be MEV to extract? And then like...
Correct. But what is the ratio? What is the ratio between me wanting to buy a dog poop
coin and the 17 guys placing fizzling orders to try and sandwich me for 1% of my swap?
That's the question. And it's not flattering.
It's not one-to-one.
I mean, that would be a beautiful world if it was.
I just want a personalized experience with my MEV bot, you know?
Yeah.
How's the urge?
It's not just like you and your counterparty in the trade. It's you, your counterparty
and 17 other people trying to get a tiny slice of it.
How do they all get a piece? Wouldn't there just be one MEV bot that recognizes the entire
opportunity and builds the whole stack and then pays the biggest bribe to Flashbots?
Right. So here's the crux of it. Because you can create these very complicated on-chain
orders using smart contracts, you can just dumbly execute them over and over again, hoping
to get something. And the worst case that happens is the transaction fizzles. It doesn't
execute because the preconditions aren't met because you're in the wrong spot in the block.
The swaps already happened. Your transaction executes something. Your condition has changed.
You still spend some gas or something putting the transaction into the chain, but this is
not productive economic activity for the most part.
And so they basically found that because you could do 100 of these and if on the 101st
dumb idiot order you win it big, it becomes positive EV for you. So basically, it's advantageous
for you to spam the blockchain with these fizzling orders in the off chance that one
of them gets through. And so these blockchains are just a glut of these insane order structures
getting pushed into every block because it is economically positive. But as a result,
also the main thing is that many of these are inert, basically. They attempted a transaction,
it failed. And the thrust of the transaction is that they spent some gas to compensate
the blockchain for doing the compute to check that their transaction failed. But they're
not transacting with anyone else.
Exactly. They're doing literally nothing. They're just clogging up the block space and
these L2s are full of it. Flashbots proposed a bunch of solutions. One of the solutions
that came out of it was EIP 1559, which basically is a progressive tax on gas. So the more clogged
the chain is, the more you have to pay. And this is to obviously disincentivize these
bots from, or at least making them find the price equilibrium that they're willing to
pay to get that transaction in.
1559 was ultrasound money, right?
Was it? Was it? That's a good question.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. Algorithmic fees, right? Am I right here?
I mean, that's one way that they marketed it. The other way they marketed it is ultrasound
money. And this is going to make everyone in Ethan, Rich is going to have a better inflation
profile than Bitcoin and gold and everything.
I do remember that, but I'm not particularly dogmatic about Ethereum or any other chain.
So I just like, I'm more interested in the sort of like way they war-gamed this out and
tried to solve this problem. So this problem is called a Tullock contest I've learned,
which is just kind of like a game theory way to model a raffle, right? Like the more tickets
you buy, in this case, the more stupid orders you place, the higher your chance of winning
is.
And so like the kind of stable equilibrium of that contest is to buy tickets right up
until the value of winning the raffle, right? Or very close to it, right? And so that of
course means that there's a lot of tickets, in this case, dumb orders in the chain. And
I think that LLM slop is maybe a little bit similar to that. Like I think that there's
like this massive incentive for people to spam, right? In any place right now, like
in my Slack DMs on Twitter, on Facebook, like it's the bot internet. And there's no corrective
mechanism. And I think like, you know, what I write in the blog is that I think there
are basically two types of corrective mechanism for the Tullock contest. One is the auction,
which is EIP 1559. You make people bid somehow on that space, on that blog space or on that
post. The other is the wall, which is that you keep people out based on some criteria,
because you know, maybe they're bots or maybe they're bad actors or something like that.
And I think like I broadly would prefer the auction, but I think we're going to get the
wall, which is, you know, like paid subscriptions or, you know, stuff like that. KYC is another
example of a wall. So that's the thrust of it.
How does the auction work though? Like, I don't know, like the way that I'm theorized,
like my mental model of this is like, okay, in order to do spam, there's some expected
value of doing the spam. Like if I shoot the shot, then maybe I have like a 1 in 100 chance
of making a dollar or something. So my expected value is one cent of doing this thing. And
then basically I will keep doing a thing with expected value of one cent, as long as it
costs me less than one cent. And so the way to like stifle this activity is just to raise
the cost of it above the expected value. So they're like, you know, the platform that
like, you know, they're spamming could just charge you a cent for spamming. And then suddenly
it would become uneconomical to spam. So that is that the wall or is that the auction? Because
it's like, I would say that's the auction because you're buying, you're somehow buying
the post now, like whether the price is set algorithmically, or like what the parameters
of that price are, I think is the interesting thing.
But it could be like a centralized platform just puts a price to post content. It doesn't
have to be like, so I wasn't when you said auction, I was like, Okay, so Chris follows
me if I want to post, I have to like every time Chris opens his feed, I have to like
bid on like, you know, the slot, the third slot in his feed for my post or something
like that.
Right. But that's that's an ad auction, right? Like, that's how? Yeah. And I mean, like another
option that I think that's horrible and dystopian, but like, that's an option, right?
Yeah. Well, especially for like a social network, where it's like a person to person kind of
situation and not like, I don't know, like if your expectation is I'm on YouTube, I'm
looking for like content to watch, and it's mostly professional content, then like maybe
that kind of makes sense. But if you're like, I'm on, I don't know, Instagram, and I want
to see like, what my homies were doing on their vacation.
Right, totally different. Or like, you're, you're on like Twitter, and you want to see
like the hottest hot take, and you don't care who posted it. But like, it needs to make
you seem funny at parties or whatever, right? Like you want the creme de la creme. I think
like, you know, paying for it degrades the quality of the content, for sure. So like,
my suggestion there would be, like, maybe we should try an EIP 1559 style gas auction,
you know, like if you maybe if you segment it by topic somehow, and then as that topic
gets congested, the cost to post goes up and up, I think it would disproportionately punish
the bots. Whether it's enough to reach a stable equilibrium, I don't know. But yeah, just
the thought that I had. It could also tell us whether we should invest
in the AI side of the podcast or the Bitcoin side of the podcast. We could just bid for
whichever one's lower, or the stable coin side of the podcast, as we're talking about
right now. The third side. Yeah. But yeah, I think like,
I think this is like a market structure that we're going to see a lot of in the future.
I don't really know if there are, like, I think that like, like, crypto has had to deal
with this for a long time. So like, I was like, let's reach into that bag and see what
they have. But I don't I don't think it maps cleanly onto the problem. And I think like,
there are going to be really good ways and really bad ways to sort this out. And I just
hope we don't do the bad ones. Like, like what you're suggesting, Tyler, for example,
like bidding on ad space, you know, to show my friend, like my what I was doing on my
vacation feels quite sinister. But yeah. But if you have to just play like a video
game for 10 seconds in your browser in a post or something like that. Proof of proof of
work algorithm was, I think, to protect against email spam, like you would have to solve this
like hash problem before you can email or receive an email. But I think, you know, I
think, you know, I mean, there's a lot of, I mean, there's a lot of, there's a lot of
problems before you can email or receive an email. But I think, you know, there are there
are lots of reasons that doesn't work, right? Like, like compute is probably cheaper for
bad actors than like me with my like, you know, MacBook Air. Yeah, and I yeah, I just
think like a lot of these problems in the limit are that we were like using these problems
to prove some kind of investment that doesn't work anymore. Like like what Tyler's saying
about proof of fun wouldn't work because Jeff would have all of the fun for you like captures
up. I didn't even know what's going on in that world. But it seems like they're in all
sorts of trouble. So they're so hard, man. They're hard for me to do the captions. I'm
like, there's a letter behind the letters that's like, basically invisible. But one
thought better at them to like, you can totally tell views, like views will be like, Oh, sorry,
there's a capsule. Like I can't proceed. And you're like, you have my permission, you can
do it, buddy. And I don't want to do it.
Yeah, that's that's what I'm worried about is these agentic, agentic homies, I've been
using instinct. And I'm like scared because what happens when everyone else starts using
instinct and views, and then we're like fighting for restaurant reservations that are already
hard to come by or fighting for Iron Man registrations, where there's all like already people built
custom bots, but now everyone has like a free open source bot that can navigate any website.
So you don't have to be clever to screw other people over.
It's just like everything becomes priced, like things that previously were just priced
based on friction are like now have to be priced economically.
Right. That's the question. Does everything become priced because that's a bad world, right?
Like say you want to take your girlfriend to dinner on Valentine's Day. And, you know,
you're living in, you know, maybe a very nice part of Manhattan. Like that could be very
expensive for you, right? Like if you're not just paying for the meal, but you're also
paying congestion pricing with everyone's agent to get a booking.
Yeah.
Yeah, like we're paying out the convenience and maybe that's like how we'll rationalize
that we're paying the convenience fee, which is this auction price of having everything
done automatically. Hopefully our salaries increase accordingly and keep up with consumer
price inflation.
Right. Maybe we'll just be doing like perpetual futures on Wendy's double daves forever. And
like, that's how it's going to be, you know, I don't know.
You just have to learn to like the things that other people don't like, you know. Okay.
That's a good strategy. Yeah.
Well, I feel like there's like in the internet age, there's like one, you know, one burrito
taqueria that gets anointed in the mission district. This is the best one, according
to Nate Silver. And then therefore, like it's the one that everyone must have. And it's
like, dude, there are literally 10 taquerias around there that serve a burrito that's indistinguishable
from that one. And like that other one is, you know, like five dollars cheaper and there's
no line. And it's great. Yeah. It's not, I'm not saying that the one that's really good
is bad. I'm saying that they're all really good.
You have to put it when you're sold by your agent to keep looking. Don't just go for the
most pricey.
Yeah. Settle for the second best, you know, it's often almost as good as the first best.
Right. Get your agent to open Google maps, branch out a little bit, you know, not just
off the top of whatever indexer it's using. And we're rolling up 3 72 on Asta, one of
the few per per fortunes for finishing up very happy about that.
I think we got to fix the structure of per per fortune to have more volatility.
Yeah. I think we need to rethink purple fortune. I think we need to, I think we need like a
small Korean lady like yelling and screaming when something like that. There's no yelling
and screaming. It's gone. Yeah.
That's true. We could just, we could, well, anyways, we're headed out. We'll discuss the
future of the purple portion off the record. You guys don't need it now. We're headed out.
Happy October, everybody.
Get free.